# SEONJIN NA

 $\begin{array}{l} Phone: \ +82\ 10\mbox{-}3027\mbox{-}8795 \\ Email: \ \mbox{sjna@casys.kaist.ac.kr} \end{array}$ 

Github: https://github.com/sjna-casys Website: https://sjna-casys.github.io

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests lie in GPU architecture, trusted computing, heterogeneous systems, distributed computing, and systems for machine learning. My current research focuses on building secure architecture to provide the trusted execution environment(TEE) on accelerators such as GPUs, and NPUs with low-performance overhead.

## **EDUCATION**

KAIST

Mar. 2018 - Present

Doctor of Philosophy, School of Computing

Advisor: Jaehyuk Huh

**KAIST** *Mar.* 2016 - Feb. 2018

Master of Science, School of Computing

Advisor: Jaehyuk Huh

Sogang University Mar. 2012 - Feb. 2016

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Summa Cum Laude

## RESEARCH PROJECTS

## Efficient On-chip Memory Management and Scheduling on NPUs

Dec. 2021 - Present

- · Investigated the performance bottleneck of DNN Training on NPUs.
- · Analyzed the data dependency of tensor computations in DNN training.
- · Proposed a efficient on-chip memory management and scheduling policy to improve DNN training performance on NPUs.

### Trusted Multi-GPU Architecture

Sep. 2021 - Present

- · Investigated the performance degradation when applying existing securing communication mechanism to multi-GPU system on the MGPU-Sim simulator.
- · Analyzed the communication patterns of various workloads running on Multi-GPU systems and proposed a dynamic security-metadata partitioning mechanism.

#### Trusted NPU Architecture

Sep. 2019 - Sep. 2021

- · Designed a TEE design for NPU integrated in processors.
- · Extended the existing CPU TEE design to isolate the context for NPU execution
- · Proposed a novel tree-less integrity protection by exploiting the tensor-based semantics of NPU execution model.
- · Measured the performance improvement compared with conventional tree-based memory protection on the Scale-Sim simulator.
- · Published in HPCA 2022

## Efficient Memory Protection Mechanism for Secure GPU Memory Sep. 2017 - Sep. 2020

- · Designed and implemented a secure GPU architecture that provides the confidentiality and integrity of the data on GPU memory with low-performance overhead.
- · Analyzed the memory update behaviors of GPU benchmark suites and real-world GPU applications on Real-GPU hardware using NVbit tool.
- · Proposed a efficient GPU memory encryption and integrity verification mechanism and evaluated the performance improvement compared to state-of-the-art memory protection techniques on the GPGPU-Sim simulator.
- · Published in HPCA 2021

#### Machine Learning Inference on Mobiles

Mar. 2019 - Jun. 2019

- · Analyzed the performance characterization of mobile ML inferences using TensorFlow Lite framework.
- · This project was done during Microsoft Research Asia internship.

## **Hardware Prefetching**

Mar. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- · Investigated and analyzed the performance of HW-based prefetching techniques on the CPU system.
- · Implemented HW-based prefetching techniques on Gem5 simulator.

### **Publications**

- · Sunho Lee, <u>Seonjin Na</u>, Jungwoo Kim, Jongse Park, and Jaehyuk Huh, "Tunable Memory Protection for <u>Secure Neural Processing Units</u>", the 40th IEEE International Conference on Computer Design (ICCD), October 2022.
- · Sunho Lee, Jungwoo Kim, **Seonjin Na**, Jongse Park, and Jaehyuk Huh, "TNPU: Supporting Trusted Execution with Tree-less Integrity Protection for Neural Processing Unit", the 28th IEEE International Symposium on High-Performance Computer Architecture (**HPCA**), February 2022.
- · Seonjin Na, Sunho Lee, Yeonjae Kim, Jongse Park, and Jaehyuk Huh, "Common Counters: Compressed Encryption Counters for Secure GPU Memory", the 27th IEEE International Symposium on High-Performance Computer Architecture (HPCA), February 2021.

### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### Microsoft Research Asia

Mar. 2019 - Jun. 2019

· Research Intern, Advisor: Lintao Zhang, Yunxin Liu

KAIST

Mar. 2016 - Present

· Graduate Research Assistant & Teaching Assistant

#### **PATENTS**

#### Apparatus and Method for Providing Secure Execution Environment for NPU

- · Jaehyuk Huh, Sunho Lee, **Seonjin Na**
- · US Patent (With Samsung Electronics); Pending

#### Hardware-based Security Architecture for Trusted Neural Processing Unit

- · Jaehyuk Huh, Sunho Lee, Seonjin Na
- · Korean Patent (With Samsung Electronics); Filling Date: 2021/07/23;

## Efficient Encryption Method and Apparatus for Hardware-based Secure GPU Memory

- · Jaehyuk Huh, Seonjin Na, Sunho Lee, Yeonjae Kim, and Jongse Park
- · Korea Patent; Filling Date: 2020/11/23; Isseud Date: 2022/02/16

## AWARDS AND HONORS

## National Scholarship, KAIST

Mar. 2016 - Present Gold Prize Nov. 2015

· The 2015 ACM-ICPC Asia Daejeon Regional Contest 4th place

**Honorable Mention** Nov. 2013

· The 2015 ACM-ICPC Asia Daejeon Regional Contest 13th place

Academic Scholarship, 8 semesters Mar. 2012 - Sep. 2015

· Sogang University

## TEACHING EXPERIENCE

## **KAIST**

· CS230 System Programming: Fall 2016, Spring 2017, Fall 2018, Fall 2020

· CS311 Computer Organization: Fall 2019

## Sogang University

· Introduction to C Programming: Winter 2014

## **SKILLS**

· Programming Languages : C/C++, Go, CUDA, Python, Java

· Library/Frameworks : NVBit, Pytorch, Tensorflow

· Simulators : GPGPU-Sim, MGPU-Sim, Gem5, Gem5-gpu, Scale-Sim